Hey, let's all stay closer together.
This is a story that happened
right before I, Shinichi Kudo...
...was turned into Conan Edogawa.
You must be Shinichi Kudo, right?
About the recent
manga artist murder case...
...you did great for figuring out
the suspect's extremely ingenious trick!
Even Chief Inspector Megure
mentioned it!
You can say that Shinichi Kudo's
unusually sharp deduction skills...
...did help us solve the case.
"Shinichi Kudo"
It's not a big deal.
I am a detective, after all.
And, if it's Holmes, whom I respect...
...could surely have solved it
in half the time and effort I took.
Excuse me.
One last word, please.
I'm in a hurry, sorry.
He's so handsome!
Please look this way!
-Good morning!
-Morning!
Ran, I can see your underwear.
"Ran Mori"
-Shinichi!
-It's light pink.
I'm just kidding, I didn't see it.
So, how do you know
what colour I was wearing?
Just a simple deduction.
One...You turned 17 yesterday.
Two...Your dad opened
the present from your mother...
...who's not living with you,
without asking.
My dad did?
I heard he told the master of
the café beneath your house.
"Ran's too early to wear something sexy
like that, what's she thinking!", or something.
Third...You would immediately
wear the present she bought you...
...because you love her.
Why is dad telling
people unnecessary things!?
But…
You don't have to be so upset.
And I don't think your dad
meant you any harm.
And you are so popular, as usual.
Help me, Ran!
You should clean up
your own mess, right?
You're so cold.
We're friends since forever, right?
You're the cold one.
Lately you stopped
giving me birthday presents.
You've never forgotten to get me
a present when we were younger.
Like 'Autobiography
of Sherlock Holmes'...
-...or 'Sherlock Holmes…'
-I don't know, okay,
I have no idea what a high school
girl would want for her birthday.
I want to go
to the amusement park!
-Tropical Land!
-Tropical Land?
We talked about it
the other day, remember?
You said you'll buy anything I want
if I won the karate competition!
I want to go to Tropical Land!
No. We're not kids anymore.
Both of you.
You're having a couple's quarrel
first thing in the morning?
Don't say weird things.
Sonoko, Ran said she wants
to go to Tropical Land with you.
I…!
Will go with Sonoko.
Let's go, Sonoko!
We're going to be late.
Come on.
Why is she angry?
I understand.
This famous detective, Kogoro Mori,
will definitely find Shunsaku's whereabouts.
Please imagine you're on a big wave.
I mean on a big boat.
Please, help me find Shunsaku.
-This is his picture.
-Okay.
-Please be careful.
-Find him for me, please.
What Shunsaku?
This is not work to be done
by the great detective Kogoro Mori.
Ah, how could I forget!
It's time for Youko's appearance.
Yoko!
I hear that you're filming
a new drama series?
Yes. I will take on a role
as a detective for the first time.
So please watch it!
Yoko as a detective?
I heard you used someone
as the model of your character.
-Yes.
-To get into your role.
-That is the famous detective…
-Kogoro Mori.
-Shinichi Kudo!
I'm a big fan of his.
I wish I could meet him just once.
Damn!
Curse that detective brat.
Gaining popularity all the time…!
I'm soaked!
Please don't forget anything.
And also, Mr. Tatsumi will be in
the hospital longer than expected.
So, I will be following you
to your trip tomorrow.
-Kitajima will be following us.
-I'm worried.
So everyone,
have a sense of responsibility...
A trip…
As student of Teitan High School,
and have a fun trip.
I want you to write a report of your
group activities and submit it...
...so please take important notes.
That's all.
Any question?
"Challenge letter to Shinichi Kudo"
I can't wait!
We haven't been on a trip
since our primary school trip, right?
Tomorrow we're going to the
art museum and then, Ashinoko.
And for the free time at night…
Shinichi, do you want
to go anywhere?
Shinichi!
I'm not joining the trip.
-Why not?
-It's a waste of time.
It's much useful to study a real case...
...no matter if it's a human
relationships or society as a whole.
So, you go have fun.
Shinichi.
"Kudo"
"Challenge letter to Shinichi Kudo"
Interesting.
"Shinichi Kudo, Shun Oguri"
"Ran Mori, Tomoka Kurokawa"
"Kogoro Mori, Takanori Jinnai"
"Challenge letter to Shinichi Kudo"
"Prologue Until Their Goodbye"
Good morning.
-Good morning, Ran.
-Good morning.
Sonoko, what's that?
Clothes, make up,
and my lucky lingerie.
Lucky lingerie?
I'll have a boyfriend
by the end of the trip.
Your passion towards love
is really something.
What are you talking about?
You are getting one too.
I don't know what so great about
detective mania, but he is very popular.
So you will have to declare to them
that you're his wife in this trip.
What's wrong, Ran?
-But Shinichi's not coming.
-Eh? Why?
He said that school trips
are a waste of time.
That idiot.
Everyone, listen here.
This is your tour conductor,
Miss Nishida.
"Tour Conductor, Mai Nishida"
I am Mai Nishida.
I will be your guide
for the next three days.
She's gorgeous!
So hot.
-Please teach me everything, Miss Mai!
-We're departing. It's time to depart.
Wait a moment!
-Sorry, Mr. Kitajima. I overslept.
-I'm glad you could make it.
Alright everyone,
get in lines and board the bus!
-Yes!
-I'm sitting in front!
What's this?
You said you're not coming.
I changed my mind.
I think that it's not bad to have fun
like a kid once in a while.
You're a kid too, right?
Isn't this a good thing?
So you can go to your
honeymoon together.
Sonoko!
A challenge letter to Shinichi Kudo.
I will kidnap one of your
classmates during your school trip.
If you can protect them, you win.
If you can't, I win.
And when that happens...
...you have to give up from
your High School Detective title.
This is a one-on-one fight
between you and me.
But I will give you one hint.
It will happen on the boat.
"Kidnapper"
That's awesome!
Look at this!
So beautiful!
Shinichi!
Hey!
Welcome 2B class
from the Teitan High School.
I am Azuma, your captain.
We will be explaining
emergency procedures...
...so please gather at the front deck.
-Hello everyone.
-Hello.
I am Minamida,
pleased to meet you.
In case of an emergency,
please put on the life jacket.
Isn't he handsome?
Like a grown up man.
I've decided on him.
-I'm going to get him.
-After you put it through your hands…
This ship will go around the lake,
which will take about 1 hour.
So, please enjoy the lakeside sceneries.
Yes.
This boat will become
a closed room for the next hour.
Come from wherever you want.
I will protect all of them.
You're Shinichi Kudo, right?
That high school detective.
-Yes.
-I'm your fan.
I'm so glad I could meet you.
Mr. Minamida,
do you have a girlfriend?
Sorry, but I have work to do.
Wait.
I will not let you go.
50 minutes left.
The ship is cruising at 20km/h.
It's nearly impossible to approach
this ship without being noticed.
If I am the Kidnapper,
I should already be on this boat.
The captain, Kunio Azuma.
The crew member, Kyosuke Minamida.
The substitute teacher, Shingo Kitajima.
And the guide, Mai Nishida.
But, no matter
who the Kidnapper is...
...taking one student
from this boat is impossible.
How do you plan to do it?
What's wrong?
You're looking scary.
Nothing.
It feels good to be on the water.
Let's take a picture together.
We used to take a lot of pictures
together, but none recently.
Say Cheese!
What's with that face?
Smile, Shinichi!
One more.
No!
Sonoko?
I feel sick.
You're seasick?
Are you alright, Suzuki?
Are you alright?
Stop sexually harassing me.
I'm feeling worse.
Sonoko.
There's a room for you to lie down.
-Kudo, help me.
-Alright.
Thank you, Mr. Minamida.
What about me?
Medicine…
I should've brought some with me!
Don't worry, I have some.
Here you go.
Please forgive me, Miss Mai.
Don't worry it is a part of my job.
Take this.
Damn...
Which princess gets seasick
even though she takes a cruiser...
...all the time at home?
You have a cruiser at home?
She may not look like it...
...but she's the daughter of
the Suzuki Financial Group. Right?
You don't have to tell me that.
Mr. Minamida,
can you stay with me?
Sorry, I have work to do.
We'll stay with Sonoko.
Me too? Alright then.
Don't push yourself too hard.
Take it easy.
And there goes Mr. Minamida.
-Sonoko.
-Don't be angry.
I'll be alright here.
Both of you should go too.
You have to make some
good memories with Shinichi.
Are you sure you're alright?
Stay here, and
don't move around, ok?
Just go.
Sonoko, lock the door
from the inside.
Don't open the door
to anyone except me.
Why?
You don't want anyone else
to see you vomiting, right?
Alright.
-What did you tell her?
-Nothing, just told her to sleep.
"Resting room"
Excuse me.
About the weather, it looks like
it will turn very bad soon.
You're right.
And one of the students is taking
a rest in the resting room...
...due to seasickness.
I don't think it's anything serious.
Is that so? Thank you.
Everyone, look this way.
Can you see it?
The Torii gates of
the Hakone Shrine in Ashinoko...
...was made in the year 757.
I'm taking the picture.
-Yes, okay.
-Thank you.
-Is it alright?
-Yes!
I'm nervous.
30 minutes left.
What's wrong, Kidnapper?
You're strange today, Shinichi.
Ever since we got
onto this cruise ship.
No, I'm not.
I can tell.
I can.
-What was that sound?
-I have no idea.
Let's take a look.
Over there!
That's Sonoko's headband!
Don't tell me that Sonoko…
From here?
Mr. Minamida.
Please tell the captain
to stop the ship immediately.
Alright!
Please be safe, Sonoko.
Sonoko… is not here.
Miss Suzuki?
What happened here?
I don't know.
One of the life jackets
that were here is missing.
Life jacket?
Then, did Miss Sonoko
really jump into the lake?
It's too early to say that.
Mr. Kitajima and Mr. Minamida.
Let's split up and search
around the boat.
Okay.
Captain, please contact
the guards around the area...
...and request for a search
near the shores.
Alright.
Miss Mai, please tell everyone
that there's nothing to worry about.
That door was properly
shut just now.
Did it open because of a struggle?
It's empty.
One person can hide in here.
Did the kidnapper hide in
here from the start?
And attacked Sonoko
when she's alone?
Then put the life jacket on her
and jumped into the lake together?
We're now at the central
southern part of Ashinoko Lake.
Yes.
I will bring the boat
to a jetty right away.
Miss Suzuki!
You heard a loud noise just now...
...but there's nothing wrong with
the boat, so you don't need to worry.
"Do Not Enter"
Anything there?
Nothing.
Let's look somewhere else.
I was controlling the boat
from the control room.
I was at the boat's front deck.
I didn't think that something
like this would happen…
Don't worry, we'll take…
Shinichi.
Let's wait inside.
Look at that!
Call the headquarters, now!
The kidnapped is Suzuki Financial
Groups' second daughter.
There's no contact
from the suspect yet.
But there's high possibility
they will ask for ransom.
Our mission is to find and ensure
the safety of Sonoko Suzuki!
-Who are you?
-Shinichi Kudo.
A detective.
-Please let me join the investigation.
-A detective?
Oh, oh!
He's the one featured on the media.
The kid that has been solving
several hard cases in Tokyo.
I have no idea how great you are.
-But this is not a place for an outsider.
-I'm not an outsider.
Sonoko is an important classmate.
Please contact Inspector Megure
from the Metropolitan Police.
Let me join the investigation.
I'm not going to listen to
the Metropolitan Police.
What are you all doing?!
-Go investigate!
-Yes.
Please wait.
Please tell just one thing.
How much oxygen was left
inside the tank that you found?
180.
-Why do you want to know?
-Nothing.
Thank you.
Hello, dad?
What?
That rich brat was kidnapped?
I'm just worried.
She's your important friend.
I promise you that I'll find her.
I'm heading down there,
wait for me.
Hello, dad?
Sonoko…
Please be safe.
Inspector Megure.
I was not allowed to join
the investigation by the local police.
I thought so.
Tamagawa is 10,000 times more
hard headed and stubborn than me.
And he is also known as...
...the non-negotiable Mount
Everest of the Prefectural Police.
-I'm sorry that I couldn't help you.
-It's okay.
I'll manage with whatever I have.
"Unknown Caller"
Yes.
Is this Shinichi Kudo?
Kidnapper.
That's me.
Sonoko better be safe.
For now, she is.
Let me out of here, you fool.
But that was too easy.
And I gave you a huge hint too.
This is boring.
So, I will take another one tomorrow.
And since you're so useless,
I'll give you an even bigger hint.
Tell me.
Tomorrow's abduction
will happen at exactly 12 noon.
Not earlier. Not later.
Till then...
I'll reveal who you are
and save Sonoko by then.
Ran…
They told you to wait at the hotel.
They told you too, right?
I'm surprised you knew I was here.
I know you'd be
investigating Sonoko's case.
And the only lead you have is here.
Here you go.
You didn't eat anything, right?
I know that when you're immersed into
a case, you'll forget everything else.
Thanks.
Let me help you.
-You're just going to get in the way.
-I want to do something.
For Sonoko.
She's my best friend.
If I'm in the same situation...
...I think Sonoko wouldn't be
able to sit down and just wait.
Damn...
You can never change your mind once
you put your mind to it, since we're kids.
Did you find anything?
Even if the suspects' footprints are here...
...it would be wiped off by the rain.
If...?
The culprit took Sonoko here
from the lake, right?
That's true.
They found a man's wetsuit and
life jacket from the ship here.
But, if this is a trick used
by the suspect…
What do you mean?
The amount left in the oxygen tank.
If there's a chance Sonoko
did jump, it should be here.
And the oxygen tank
was found here.
Too much oxygen left in the tank,
even if they swam in a straight line.
The suspect left the evidence
here in advance...
...so that we would think that
it is done by an outsider.
So, the suspect was
on the ship at the time?
I have no idea.
But, it looks like we have to
investigate the ship one more time.
Let's go over what happened again.
When we heard the sound...
Everyone was at the front deck.
The captain,
Azuma was steering the ship.
So it is impossible for anyone
on the boat to kidnap her.
I bet someone was hiding
and kidnapped Sonoko.
No, those four is still suspicious.
It's possible to create
an alibi using tricks.
Trace of gunpowder...
-Just as I thought.
-Gunpowder?
For example, you tie
a weight using a rope here.
And place a small ignition
device to burn the ropes.
The weight will fall into the lake...
...and create an illusion that
someone jumped into the lake.
Meaning, Sonoko was kidnapped
before we heard the sound.
Then where was she?
She was not on the boat.
Was she dumped in the lake and
we can never find her again?
Right?
Don't worry.
Sonoko was safe.
She was?
What do you mean?
Shinichi!
I'll confess.
A challenge letter was sent to me.
It was sent by the 'Kidnapper'.
It wrote, "I will kidnap one of your
classmates during your school trip."
And just now, I received a call from the suspect
about plans of a second abduction.
He's going to kidnap another
student tomorrow at noon.
When I received the phone call,
I heard Sonoko's voice.
Ran?
Why?
Why didn't you contact the police
when you receive the challenge letter?
These aren't games, you know?
Detective should not put lives of
people around them in danger!
I don't think this is a game.
This is… a match between me and him.
Match?
Is there any point in having a match
with a coward like him?
There is a point.
It is because the suspect is a coward.
If I run away from this...
...he might do something
even worse the next time.
It's written in the challenge letter.
If I break the one-on-one condition,
it could cause him to do something worse.
And...
And what?
No. Nothing.
Anyway, for now...
...we need to think how to stop him
from executing the second crime.
And to catch him during the act.
That's all we can do now.
Sometimes you should trust me, Ran.
I trust you.
But in exchange, no more secrets.
Alright. I'll agree with that.
As all of you know...
A second kidnapping will happen
exactly at 12 noon today.
So, we the prefectural police...
...have discussed with
the school and as a result...
...we have agreed that
it would be safer for you...
...to be in this hotel
at the predicted time of crime...
...than bringing you back to Tokyo.
So at noon,
everyone will gather in this hall.
And we will lock all
five entrances from within...
...and create a closed room.
So, the kidnapper won't be able
to get close to any of you.
Impressive.
And...!
There will be 5 policemen
standing outside each door.
Furthermore,
there are policemen...
...standing guard at every
usable entrance of this hotel.
Meaning, you have 3 layers
of security guarding you.
So I want you to be relaxed
and wait for noon to come.
There's one more layer of security!
Let go of me, you fools.
-Dad!
-Uncle.
-Who do you think you are!?
-Sorry to keep you waiting.
I am the famous detective,
Kogoro Mori.
And I am also Ran's father.
Another detective...?
I will gladly help with
the investigation.
A parent like should not butt in
an investigation like this.
-But I am a famous detective.
-Everyone!
Please return to your own room...
...and return to this hall and
wait for us when you're ready.
-That is all.
-That's all!
You must wait!
-Dad! You really came.
-Of course.
How can I sit still
when you're in danger?
That inspector doesn't let even me
to join the investigation.
So I think it'd be
impossible for you too.
Stupid police pride.
I will be here to protect
everyone at noon.
I want you to look
around the outside.
But don't get in the way
of the guards, ok?
Yes.
Don't tell me what to do!
Dad, please take care of the outside.
-It's for Sonoko.
-I know.
I guess I'll leave the inside
to you, detective brat.
-Ok, don't mess up.
-Stop talking to me like that.
Alright. I'll go and take
a look around, first.
I'll be checking this hall,
just to be safe.
Ran, go rest in your room.
You didn't sleep well since
yesterday night, right?
Alright.
Sonoko…
Shinichi will catch the culprit soon.
Just hold on till then.
What's this?
-Miss Fukuda?
-Yes.
-Mr. Miyoshi?
-Mr. Morimoto?
-Yes.
Alright, so everyone's here.
We're in the basement.
The only 5 doors available
are locked from the inside.
There are police stationed
outside the doors.
And only Inspector Tamagawa
has the master key to the doors.
The air vents are too small
for humans to pass through.
This time, it really is a closed room.
So, where will you come from?
This is the famous detective,
Kogoro Mori.
Detective brat, the guard outside is perfect.
I don't think even a mouse can get in.
-It is perfect here too.
-Okay.
But if something does happen…
I'll leave Ran in your care.
Damn, I didn't think I'd ever
need to say that line.
I know, Uncle.
In here, we only need to be
careful of one person.
Everyone, gather around.
-Teacher!
-Don't worry.
You have nothing to worry about.
-There's only 5 minutes left.
-Let's go quickly.
It's okay.
Don't worry.
The culprit doesn't have to be a man.
She could be a woman too.
Don't overlook the older people
and children too!
Excuse me,
are you authorized to be here?
I am Kogoro Mori,
the famous detective.
I am Mai Nishida.
I am the guide in charge
of the school trip.
And I got caught in Sonoko Suzuki's
kidnapping incident and…
So I'm worried about them.
Mr. Azuma, Mr. Minamida...
They are also people
who got caught in the incident.
The ship's captain, Mr. Azuma.
And the crew member, Mr. Minamida.
-This Mr. Mori, a detective.
-A famous detective.
I couldn't just sit still...
Thinking that something
could happen again.
Don't worry.
There's another bratty detective
inside there with them.
Don't let go, no matter what.
You have nothing to worry about!
This is the corridor in front of
the main hall. All okay.
It's alright.
Don't worry.
I won't let anything happen.
Okay.
But, I feel nervous every time I think
about what's happening to Sonoko.
The only thing we should think about
is how two win this second attempt.
That's all.
You're right.
It's nearly 12 noon.
Everyone stay at their position!
Another 45 seconds left.
Kidnapper, bring it on!
This Kogoro Mori will defeat you.
Sorry, but I need to go
to the toilet.
Me too, I need to make
a phone call.
What are they doing
at a time like this?
Everyone, calm down!
It's okay!
The lights went out!
It's too dark to see anything!
What, a black out? What happened?
Get the power back up!
Get the power running quickly!
Everyone stay at their positions!
I wonder if they are all alright.
Is everyone alright?
Ran…
Ran!
Where is she?
You suspect me?
I was with these 2 the whole time.
We were scared, so we held
onto him the whole time.
Me, too.
All the doors are still locked.
What's the meaning of this?
Ran!
Ran!!!
What's the situation there?
-Tell me the situation there!
-Sorry.
What?
A student disappeared?
-What? What's happening?
-We don't have enough details yet.
Uncle!
What happened down there?
I heard they say someone disappeared,
but the room was a closed room, right?
-So how was she taken?
-What was the police doing?
And…Who was taken?!
Uncle.
Ran disappeared.
What?
Shinichi!
You useless!
Didn't I tell you to take care of Ran?
I did, right?
What are you doing?
Calm down!
Let me go!
How could you take Ran!
It's my win, again.
I guess you can't even
protect your friends...
...even though the police
was on your side.
Continuing a game like this
will get boring...
...so this will be the last one.
I have a bomb set at the place
where those two are kept.
It will detonate at exactly
12 midnight, tonight.
So, you think you can find it?
12 hours left.
Uncle.
I apologize.
For punching you.
No, I need to thank you.
I can't hit myself as hard as that.
But what is going on with this case?
Making a person
disappear easily like that.
Is the suspect a psychic?
The suspect's a normal person...
...but with a deep shadow in his heart.
I got another call from the suspect.
He said that he set up a bomb at
the place he's keeping both of them.
-The time limit is midnight.
-What?
We have to find it, no matter what!
But…
We don't know the suspect's identity,
and how he does it.
How do you expect to find him?
And we have close
to zero clues to him.
The only thing the police found was
that weird red ink on that door handle.
Red ink?
After the light turned back on, I ran out of that door to look for Ran.
But I didn't notice any red ink
on the door handle back then.
Then, does that mean
after you ran out...
...one of the student touched it
and left the red ink?
Then that will not be a good clue.
I guess all options are sealed to us.
No, there are clues…
You have an idea?
Remember what Mr. Minamida
and Miss Mai said just now?
I felt like one of them said
something weird.
What is it? Do your best
to remember it, even if you'd die!
-I heard they say someone disappeared.
-The room was closed, right?
-So how was she taken?
-What was the police doing?
Damn, what is it…
What feels off?
At least I know that it is impossible
for Miss Mai to commit the crime.
Why?
She was with me the entire time.
The entire time? Are you sure?
The ones that are suspicious are...
...the captain, Azuma
and the guy Minamida.
Why do you think that?
Minamida went to make a phone
call just before the blackout.
And Captain Azuma
hasn't return from the toilet!
That settles it.
The kidnapper is Azuma.
He must be the suspect
for the first case as well.
But, Mr. Azuma was steering
the ship when the first case happened.
You're still young, so naïve.
It's on auto-pilot.
Letting the ship steer itself,
he made an alibi for himself.
In the meantime,
he went to kidnap Sonoko.
How did he get Ran?
You just have to catch him
and we'll know how he did it.
We have no time, hurry!
We're going in.
Don't tell me…
I knew it. He was the culprit.
Damn it.
We won't know
where Ran is if he's dead.
Hey, why you just sitting there?
Help me!
I wonder what does this arrow
on the back of this will.
It's a bit dark, but it looks like
it's written with blood.
Why is there a wound there?
Uncle.
He didn't do it.
What?
He was murdered by the real culprit.
Sonoko, wake up.
Ran.
Let's run away.
Anybody there? Help us!
Anyone!?
-This is the only door, right?
-Yes.
-The only window are on the ceiling.
-What will happen to us?
Don't worry.
I'm sure Shinichi will come save us.
Actually, both of you an ideal couple.
Shinichi and you.
You're always fighting...
...but you can still believe in each
other in situations like this.
It's beautiful.
That's a bomb, right?
Are we going to die?
Ran, that dangerous!
I have no idea what to do.
But it looks like we still have time.
I wanted to fall in love
at least once before I die.
Why are you talking like that?
You can still fall in love,
as deeply as you want, after this.
-You can't give up.
-But what can we do?
-My leg hurts…
-You have to stop it.
We won't be able to watch your
turning kick if you continue kicking like that.
There's no point in me
learning karate...
...if I don't use it
in situations like this.
Ran…
Shinichi will never give up
right till the end.
Won't give up!
Ran! That's enough.
Stop!
-Ran!
-Ouch!
-I think I cracked a bone in there.
-You think?
How can you say that
with that cute face?
Sonoko, let's go, hurry.
-We can't.
-Why?
What should we do now?
I can't jump with my foot like this.
Sonoko, you go.
Tell Shinichi of this place.
I can't. I can't jump down.
And I can't leave you here all alone!
If you stay here, both of us could die!
Ran!
I promise to bring Shinichi here,
so please wait for us!
At least Sonoko is saved.
Ran, sorry.
Search Azuma's belongings
and find Ran's location, quickly!
-There's a bomb that will blow up!
-We're in the middle of it!
But!
It looks like you've been snooping around,
so I hope you didn't take anything with you.
Of course I didn't.
I used to be an inspector!
Preserving the crime scene
is the number one rule!
What's wrong?
Nothing's wrong.
That Detective Brat, what is
he planning to do with the will?
Inspector Megure, I need you
to check something for me.
This is the most suspicious room.
Just as I thought…
Now I know how
they kidnapped Sonoko.
There's no mistake,
that person did it.
But, how did they kidnap Ran?
The only thing the police found was
that weird red ink on that door handle.
Ink on the door handle?
Why is it on my hand?
Sonoko's my best friend.
If I'm in the same situation...
...I think Sonoko wouldn't be
able to sit down and just wait.
Don't tell me…
But that would explain everything.
This is Megure.
-I got the result you asked.
-Alright.
Understand.
Thank you.
And another thing.
Kudo, I believe in you.
So take care of them.
An hour left.
Damn it!
-Yes?
-Uncle, it's me.
Where and what are you doing?
I got a clue on where
they're keeping Ran.
-Tell me.
-We'll talk later.
There are 5 possible locations.
We have to split up
and look for the place.
Alright.
Wait a second.
-You are still here?!
-I have a clue to their location.
Please look at this location.
We will do things our way without
taking orders from anybody...
...especially not from a detective.
What?
I'll show you the detective spirit that
doesn't rely on organizations and titles!
Ran.
Ran!
Ran! Sonoko!
It was you.
Miss Mai Nishida.
What a coincidence.
Why are you here?
Did you come to check on it?
To check whether
the bomb is moving or not.
Bomb?
-What are you talking about?
-Don't play a fool!
I want you to release
Ran and Sonoko.
You're very rude.
You're talking like
I'm the bad guy here.
It bothered me all this time.
The words you said,
just after the second kidnapping.
So how was she taken?
Back then, how did you know
that a female student was kidnapped?
Even the police didn't have
any concrete information.
-There's no reason to it.
-No, of course there is.
The reason is…
You're the one who did it.
So then please tell me...
How did I kidnap them both?
As you wish.
For the first case...
...you set up a weight at the deck
behind the boat beforehand.
Made a device that
will burn the rope...
...and release the weight
when the time comes.
And made it to look like
an outsider' job by putting traces...
...that would look like
someone's hiding in the room.
And to make it look like Sonoko was
thrown into the lake, you stole a life jacket.
Then you placed a man's wetsuit,
oxygen tank and life jacket at the shore...
...finishing your preparation.
And on the day of crime,
you gave sleeping pills to Sonoko...
...telling it her it was to help
with her seasickness.
And you entered into the room
using the spare key you prepared earlier.
And hid the sleeping Sonoko
somewhere.
You took just the headband,
and using the device you made...
...you threw it into the lake while
everyone was distracted by the sound.
That's Sonoko's headband!
And that is how you made it
look like Sonoko fell into the lake.
Wait a moment.
We searched the ship after that,
but Miss Sonoko was not there.
It's not she was not there,
we just couldn't find her.
Because of a simple trick.
-Trick?
-A mirror.
Back then, Sonoko was inside
the closet in the opposite room.
It's a method frequently
used in magic tricks.
By using the mirror's reflection...
...it makes people think
there's nothing inside the closet.
A very simple trick.
After the police went out of the ship...
...you removed the concealing mirror
and then truly kidnapped Sonoko.
I found these, traces from the mirror.
But anybody could do that,
not just me.
And besides, during the second
kidnapping, I was outside all the time.
Moreover, I was standing
right beside Mr. Kogoro Mori.
At a glance, it seems
impossible for you to kidnap Ran.
But, it's an easy thing to do
if you use that one method, right?
Using that repulsive method.
Ran… wasn't kidnapped.
She left… on her own.
You most probably slipped in
a threat letter to Ran.
What's this?
As well as the spare key
to Grand Hall.
Sonoko Suzuki was kidnapped
by mistake instead of you.
If you want to save her life...
...leave the hall at noon.
If you tell anyone,
Sonoko will be killed.
And after that, you made her
to disguise herself as a hotel staff...
...and told her to come here, right?
Ran, who has a strong sense of justice
couldn't talk to even me about this matter.
All by herself…
To use her concern for her best friend
against her to commit your crimes...
...you're the worse!
Yes, Mr. Azuma is really the worst.
He committed suicide, didn't he?
I saw it on the news just now.
Suicide?
Was Azuma the one who did it?
They found the will too,
so there's no mistaking it.
You lost.
You just admitted you did the crime.
How did you know Azuma wrote a will?
-I said I saw it on the news.
-No way!
Because I took it
with me by mistake.
Before the police got
to the crime scene.
I just assumed it.
It said it looked like suicide,
so I thought there must be a will.
You really don't know
when to stop, do you?
This will was written by Azuma,
after he was forced by the real culprit.
And as proof...
The real culprit's spelling is K-I-D-N-A-P-P-E-R.
But Azuma's spelling was, K-I-D-N-A-P-E-R.
It's missing one 'P'.
They are both correct.
But normally one person would not
use 2 ways to spell a word, right?
And this will has clear proof
that you're the one who did it.
The message Azume wrote
with everything he got.
What message is that?
A Kidnapper...Mai.
The kidnapper is Mai.
And that is you.
So you must know this,
because you're here.
The reason why
I sent you the challenge letter.
You're the girlfriend of a man
I put behind bars...
...after helping with
the investigation, in the past.
That man was running
a wholesale company.
But he started committing crime
after getting cornered by his debts.
-And he died in prison.
-There's no time left.
Where's Ran?
You will not get away
even if you do that.
I never intended
to run away for the start.
Ran!
Are you alright, Ran?
Shinichi.
You fool, you're too reckless.
Sorry.
Sorry for not realizing it sooner.
This was your biggest SOS
sign to me, right?
No.
It was a sign to say that I believe you.
I knew that you'd come.
Ran!
So, all 3 of us will die here.
Ran, are you in there?
Ran!
No use.
Can you stop doing this?
If you want to hate anyone,
hate you lover!
-Don't bring us into this!
-It's true.
He is the one at fault.
But, I loved him.
I had to hate someone
or I couldn't continue living.
-This life without him.
-At least let Ran live.
She's important to me,
more important than my life.
You're important to her as well.
So killing only you
would be cruel to her.
If I let her live, all she can do to live
a life like a zombie, just like I did.
-Ran is not weak.
-Are you sure?
If you disappear, even she will…
Both of you can't be separated.
No matter what.
Shinichi!
This time…!
Go!
Thank you, Uncle.
It's really the end, now.
They are all white cables.
Which one should I cut?
I made it so no one can stop it.
So…
I don't know either.
Shinichi?
It's alright, Ran.
And that is how the case is solved.
Get in.
-Let's go.
-Yes.
Dad. I'm sorry.
Don't say anything.
Thank you.
For saving Ran.
It's all thanks to your assistance.
Hmm!
Both Ran, and Sonoko,
who was found nearby, was safe.
Both of you!
What are you thinking by taking
evidence away from the crime scene?
You, you said you were
an inspector, right?
You must say nonsense like that!
But this case was solved
because of that will!
That is a different topic than this!
Both of us were yelled at.
Ran's foot got better. She entered
the karate competition and won.
And to celebrate, I was forced
to go to Tropical Land with her.
That day would change my life,
and I had no idea.
Hm, coming to
a theme park at this age.
"The Cases of Sherlock Holmes"
"Conan Doyle"
-Hurry up, Mitsuhiko, Ayumi!
-Wait, Genta!
You'll fall if you keep running like that!
Ow, I fell on my face.
Oh, you're here already.
Let's go.
Let's go to the roller coaster first.
The last time we came, we were
around those kids' age, right?
-Really?
-Yes!
I was not that short.
Let's go back to that time
and have some fun!
Okay.
Oh, right...!
What were you
trying to tell me, back then?
If I run away from this, he might do
something even worse the next time.
And…
-I forgot.
-Eh?
It's nothing important.
Let's go.
-Tell me.
-No way.
And…
I didn't want to worry you.
Because you looked forward
to the school trip so much.
While in Tropical Land with Ran...
...I saw a group of suspicious men
in black and went after them.
And that was the last time
I saw Ran as Shinichi.
I was attacked by the men in black,
and when I was unconscious...
...they made me
take an unknown drug.
And when I woke up,
my body had been shrunken.
My name is Shin…oh, no!
Conan!
My name is Conan Edogawa!